





WHO AM I?

I'm an enthusiastic machine learning engineer with a background in theoretical physics. I like solving problems, automation, clean code, and corny jokes. During my time at Catawiki I progressed into more of an MLE position when I designed and led the migration our data science platform from a PaaS to Kubernetes on GCP. This is how I discovered my passion for software that lets ML practitioners do their work with minimal cognitive overhead. I continued this pursuit at Booking.com, working on providing a seamless experience to ML users solving business problems at scale.



EXPERIENCE

2022 – present Senior Machine Learning Engineer

Booking.com

Machine Learning Platform track, Model Building team:

- Technical lead on a new LLM Evaluation Orchestration framework to enable automated quality control of LLM outputs (AWS, Python, LLM providers).
- Developed a new self-service platform for ML model development and training in AWS, fully integrated into the Booking internal ecosystem (AWS, Terraform, GitLab CI).
- Providing workshops & support for (potential) users, ensuring well-structured documentation, mentoring colleagues.

2020 - 2022 Lead Data Scientist - Machine Learning

Catawiki

- Ownership of Catawiki's data science & machine learning platform (Google Kubernetes Engine, various GCP managed services, FastAPI+nginx model serving framework).
- Developed a "one-stop-shop" ML service providing anti-fraud intelligence asynchronously to various services (classical ML, Kafka, MySQL).
- Development and maintenance of several existing ML models & applications in the domains of Engagement and Fraud Prevention (classical ML, LightFM recommender).

2019 – 2020 Senior Data Scientist - Machine Learning

Catawiki

- Lead migration of all Data Science infrastructure from a PaaS to an in-house platform on Kubernetes (Google Kubernetes Engine).
- Revamped recommendations model, improving coverage, training times, and predictive power, using a (customized variant of) LightFM.
- Created user trustworthiness model, allowing trusted users to have a less restrictive experience with minimized risk to the company.

2016 – 2019 Data Scientist & Consultant

KPMG

Maximizing the value of data for clients through exploratory data analyses, data science proofs of concept, and production machine learning projects as part of the Advanced Analytics & Big Data team. Advisory services for organizations seeking to become more data-driven.

EDUCATION

2014 - 2016 M.Sc. Theoretical Physics

Uppsala University

Followed the "Strings and Quantum Fields" track, including quantum field theory, string theory, general relativity, and various other topics from physics and mathematics. Graduated in June 2016 after the completion of a one semester (30ECT) master thesis on string theory.

2011 – 2014 **B.Sc. Physics**

Amsterdam University College

Joint international honors academy of the University of Amsterdam and the VU University Amsterdam. Graduated *summa cum laude* with a thesis on computational plasma physics for fusion energy.

LANGUAGES

English - native

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

TECHNIQUES & METHODOLOGIES

Dutch - fluent **Python** - advanced **HCL** - professional **Javascript** - basic

Git, Kubernetes, GCP (Kubernetes Engine, BigQuery, Cloud Build), AWS, Terraform, Docker, SciPy stack, scikit-learn, (Py)Spark, FastAPI, nginx, Kafka, GitLab CI Mathematical background, classical ML, recommendations, microservices, CI/CD, MLOps, Infrastructure as Code (IaC), cloud native machine learning, open source software